const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",o="chemistry",i=200,a=120,t=[{id:80,question:"Neutral atoms of neon with atomic number 10 have the same number of electrons as",option:{a:"O2+",b:"Ca2+",c:"K+",d:"Mg2+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:95,question:"If an equilibrium reaction has   H>0, the reaction will proceed favourably in the forward direction at",option:{a:"High temperature",b:"Any temperature",c:"Low temperature",d:"Minimum temperature"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:198,question:"Which of the following are structural isomers",option:{a:"Propanoic acid and propan-1, 2-diol",b:"Ethanoic acid and propanoic acid",c:"Ethan-1, 2 –diol and ethanoic acid",d:"Propanal and propanone"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:182,question:"The pressure of 100cm3 of oxygen at 350C is 750mmHg. What will be the volume of the gas if the pressure is reduced to 100mmHg  without changing the temperature",option:{a:"850cm3",b:"750cm3",c:"650cm3",d:"580cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:228,question:"The volume of 2.5 moles of oxygen at s.t.p is",option:{a:"56.0dm3",b:"84.0dm3",c:"50.0dm3",d:"20.0dm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:21,question:"What current in amperes will deposit 2.7g of aluminium in 2 hours [Al = 27, f = 96500 C mol-1]",option:{a:"32",b:"8",c:"4",d:"16"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:227,question:"The order in which a mixture of sand ammonium chloride and sodium chloride can be separated is",option:{a:"Sublimation   dissolution  filtration  evaporation",b:"Dissolution  dryness  filtration  evaporation",c:"Filtration  sublimation  evaporation  dryness",d:"Dissolution  filtration  sublimation  evaporation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:289,question:"Which of the following is used as a rocket fuel",option:{a:"CH3COOH",b:"H2SO4",c:"HCL",d:"HNO3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:118,question:"Ethanol reacts with excess acidified K2Cr2O7 to produce",option:{a:"Ethanoic acid",b:"Ethanol",c:"Ethyl ethanoate",d:"Ethanoic acid"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:144,question:"Which of the following acts as both a reducing and an oxidizing agent",option:{a:"H2",b:"SO2",c:"H2S",d:"CO2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:22,question:"Ethanoic acid is",option:{a:"Tribasic",b:"Unionizeable",c:"Monobasic",d:"Dibasic"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:63,question:"Which of the following statements is true of a proton.",option:{a:"The total mass of the protons in a particular nucleus always half the nuclear mass",b:"The mass of a proton is 1840 times the mass of an electron",c:"The mass proton is 1.0008g",d:"The mass of a proton is one-twelfth the molar mass of carbon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:286,question:"In the preparation of oxygen by heating KCIO3 in the presence of MnC2, only moderate hear is needed because the catalyst acts by",option:{a:"Increasing the surface area of the reactant",b:"Increasing the rate of the reaction",c:"Lowering the energy barrier of the reaction",d:"Lowering the pressure of the reaction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:299,question:"The final products of the reaction between methane and chloride in the presence of ultraviolet light are hydrogen chloride and",option:{a:"Dichloromethane",b:"Tetrachloromethane",c:"Chloromethane",d:"Trichloromethane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:137,question:"A carcinogenic substance is",option:{a:"Asbestos dust",b:"Sawdust",c:"Nitrogen(II) oxide",d:"Carbon (II) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:133,question:"Chlorine consisting of two isotopes of mass numbers 35 and 37 in the ratio 3:1 has an atomic mass of 35.5. Calculate the relative abundance of the isotope of mass number 37.",option:{a:"20",b:"25",c:"60",d:"75"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:37,question:"Proteins in acid solution undergo",option:{a:"Polymerization",b:"Substitution",c:"Fermentation",d:"Hydrolysis"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:129,question:"A given volume of methane diffuses in 20s. how long will it take the same volume of sulphur(IV) oxide to diffuse under the same conditions    [C = 12, H = 1, S = 32, O = 16]",option:{a:"5s",b:"20s",c:"40s",d:"60s"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:102,question:"When sugar is dissolved in tea, the reaction is always accompanied by",option:{a:"Positive entropy change",b:"Negative entropy change",c:"No entropy change",d:"A minimum entropy change"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:71,question:"Which of the following gives a precipitate when treated with NaOH solution",option:{a:"Na2CO3",b:"CH3COONa",c:"NH4Cl",d:"AlCl3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:47,question:"The formula CH2O for ethanoic acid is regarded as its",option:{a:"General formula",b:"Structural formula",c:"Molecular formula",d:"Empirical formula"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:168,question:"In the production of soap, concentrated sodium chloride solution is added to",option:{a:"Increase the solubility of the soap",b:"Decrease the solubility of the soap",c:"Saponify the soap",d:"Emulsify the soap"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:100,question:"In the electrolysis of a concentrated solution of sodium chloride using inert electrodes, which of the following ions are discharged at the cathode and anode respectively",option:{a:"Na+ and Cl-",b:"Na+ and OH-",c:"H+ and OH-",d:"H+ and Cl-"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:23,question:"C(s) + 2S (g)  → CS2 (g)      Δ H = +89kJ mol-1. The chemical equation above implies that",option:{a:"Each of carbon and sulphur has 89kJ of energy",b:"Both carbon and sulphur contribute 89kJ of energy",c:"89kJ of energy is released",d:"89kJ is absorbed"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:115,question:"The leachate of a certain plant ash is used in local soap making because it contains",option:{a:"Sodium chloride and potassium hydroxide",b:"Sodium hydroxide",c:"Potassium hydroxide",d:"Soluble carbonates and hydrogen carbonates"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:276,question:"The acid that is used to remove rust is",option:{a:"Hydrochloric",b:"Trioxonitrate (V)",c:"Tetraoxosulphate (VI)",d:"Boric"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:290,question:"A constituent common to moist air, it gradually rusts. This is due to the formation of",option:{a:"Silver",b:"Copper",c:"Tin",d:"Lead"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:12,question:"Pure solvents are obtained by",option:{a:"Distillation",b:"Condensation",c:"Extraction",d:"EvapopraTION"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:191,question:"The component of an atom that contributes least to its mass is the",option:{a:"Nucleus",b:"Neutron",c:"Electron",d:"Proton"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:152,question:"Which of the following gases can be collected by the method of downward delivery",option:{a:"Chlorine",b:"Oxygen",c:"Ammonia",d:"Hydrogen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:143,question:"ZnO(s) + CO (g) → Zn(s) + CO2 (g). ",option:{a:"Decomposed",b:"Displaced",c:"Oxidized",d:"Reduced"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:92,question:"Farmlands affected by crude –oil spillage can be decontaminated by",option:{a:"Adding acidic solutions",b:"Using aerobic bacteria",c:"Pouring water on the affected area",d:"Burning off the oil from the area"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:94,question:"A charge in the temperature of a saturated solution disturbs the equilibrium between the",option:{a:"Dissolved solute and the solvent",b:"Solvent and the undissolved solute",c:"Dissolved solute and the undissolved solute",d:"Dissolved solute and the solution"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:292,question:"A compound gives an orange red colour to a non luminous flame. This compound is likely to contain",option:{a:"Ca2+",b:"Fe3+",c:"Fe2+",d:"Na+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:43,question:"Which of the followinig respresents hybridization in ethyne?",option:{a:"Sp2",b:"Sp2d",c:"Sp3",d:"sp"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:130,question:"An electron can be added to a halogen atom to form a halide ion with",option:{a:"2 valence electrons",b:"3 valence electrons",c:"7 valence electrons",d:"Valence electrons"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:51,question:"Which of the following solutions containing only hydroxyl ions will liberate hydrogen gas when reacted with magnesium metal",option:{a:"1.0 x 10-2 mol dm-3",b:"1.0 x 10-4 mol dm -3",c:"1.0 x 10-5 mol dm-3",d:"1.0 x 10-12 mol dm-3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:278,question:"The colour of methyl orange in alkaline medium is",option:{a:"Pink",b:"Orange",c:"Red",d:"Yellow"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:165,question:"Vulcanization involves the removal of",option:{a:"A monomer",b:"The single bond",c:"The double bond",d:"A polymer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:274,question:"Coffee stains can best be removed by",option:{a:"Turpentine",b:"A solution of borax in water",c:"Ammonia solution",d:"Kerosene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:29,question:"NH3(g)  +  HCI(g)  → NH4CI(s) The entropy change in the system is",option:{a:"Negative",b:"Indeterminate",c:"Positive",d:"Zero"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:142,question:"The oxidation state of chlorine in HClO4 is",option:{a:"-5",b:"-1",c:"1",d:"7"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:74,question:"The boiling of fat and aqueous caustic soda is referred as",option:{a:"Saponification",b:"Esterification",c:"Acidification",d:"Hydrolysis"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:187,question:"An element will readily form an electrovalent compound if its electron configuration is",option:{a:"2,8,8",b:"2,,8,4",c:"2,8,5",d:"2,8,1"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:183,question:"What is the valence shell electron configuration of the element with atomic number 17",option:{a:"1s22s22p63s23p5",b:"1s22s22p63s23p4",c:"3s23p5",d:"2s22p6"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:245,question:"When 5.0cm3 of a saturated solution of sugar of molar mass 342g at 400C was evaporated to dryness, 34.2g of dry solid was obtained. The solubility of sugar at 400C is",option:{a:"7.0 mol dm-3",b:"3.5 mol dm-3",c:"2.0 mol dm-3",d:"10.0mol dm-3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:265,question:"Moving from left to right across a period, the general rise in the first ionization energy can be attributed to the",option:{a:"Increase in nuclear charge",b:"Decrease in screening effect",c:"Increase in screening effect",d:"Decrease in nuclear charge"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:240,question:"CH3-CH2-C = CH  The hybridization in the compound above is",option:{a:"Sp3 and sp",b:"Sp3 and sp2",c:"Sp",d:"Sp2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:73,question:"The gas that gives brown colouration in brown ring test",option:{a:"Co2",b:"NO2",c:"NO",d:"CO"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:212,question:"What will happen if an aluminum spoon is used to stir a solution of iron (II) trioxonitrate(V)",option:{a:"The spoon will be reduced while the iron(II) ions will be oxidized",b:"The spoon will be oxidized while the iron (II) ions will be reduced to the metal",c:"The spoon will be reduced",d:"The spoon will increase in size"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:126,question:"What volume of gas is evolved at s.t.p. if 2g of calcium trioxocarbonate(IV) is added to a solution of hydrochloric acid    [Ca = 40, C = 12, O = 16, CI = 35.5, H = 1, Molar volume of a gas at s.t.p = 22.4dm3]",option:{a:"112cm3",b:"224cm3",c:"448cm3",d:"224cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:204,question:"The air around smelting industries is likely to contain",option:{a:"CO2, SO3 and H2",b:"SO2N2 and CO2",c:"H2, SO2 and CO2",d:"H2S, CO and N2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:65,question:"A fixed mass of gas has a  volume of 92cm3 at 30C. What will be be its volume at 180C if the pressure remains constant",option:{a:"15.3cm3",b:"87.3cm3",c:"97.0cm3",d:"552.0cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:179,question:"NH4CI(g) ⇌   NH3(g)  +  HCI(g)   The reaction above can only attain equilibrium if",option:{a:"It is in a closed system",b:"It is in an open system",c:"One of the products is removed",d:"A gaseous reactant is added"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:211,question:"What is the correct IUPAC name for NO2",option:{a:"Dioxonitrate(III) ion",b:"Dioxonitrate(IV) ION",c:"trioxonitrate(iii) ion",d:"trioxonitrate(iv) ion"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:178,question:"The most suitable metal that can be used as a lightening  conductor is",option:{a:"Aluminium",b:"Iron",c:"Copper",d:"Silver"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:17,question:"In which of the following reactuions does reduction take place",option:{a:"Fe2+ - e-   Fe3+",b:"2O2-  → O2 + 4e-",c:"Cr - 2e-  → Cr2+",d:"2H+  +  2e-   →H2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:75,question:"What volume of oxygen is produced from the decomposition of 2 moles of KClO3 at s.t.p   [Molar volume of a gas at s.t.p = 22.4 dm3]",option:{a:"22.4 dm3",b:"33.6 dm3",c:"44.8 dm3",d:"67.2 dm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:141,question:"What volume of 0.5mol dm-3 H2SO4 will exactly neutralize 20cm3 of 0.1 mol dm-3 NaOH solution",option:{a:"2.0cm3",b:"5.0cm3",c:"6.8cm3",d:"8.3cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:234,question:"A degree in atomic size and an increase in knuckler charge across a period lead to",option:{a:"A decrease in covalency in bond formation",b:"An increase in chemical reactivity",c:"An increase in the tendency to loss electrons",d:"A decrease in electro positivity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:53,question:"The property which makes alcohol soluble in water is the",option:{a:"Hydrogen bonding",b:"Covalent nature",c:"Ionic character",d:"Boiling point"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:190,question:"Which of these properties gives a solid its definite shape",option:{a:"Weak intermolecular attraction",b:"High boiling point",c:"High melting point",d:"Strong intermolecular attraction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:162,question:"An isomer of C5H12 is",option:{a:"Butane",b:"2-methylbutane",c:"2-methylprpane",d:"2-ethylbutane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:6,question:"Milikan’s contribution to the development of atomic theory is the determination of",option:{a:"Charge on electron",b:"Positive rays",c:"Charge to amss ratio",d:"Cathode rays"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:174,question:"To obtain pure carbon(II) oxide from its mixture with carbon (IV)oxide, the mixture should be",option:{a:"Bubbled through concentrated Tetraoxosulphate(VI) acid",b:"Bubbled through sodium hydroxide",c:"Passed over heated copper(II) oxide",d:"Bubbled through water"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:199,question:"The enzyme responsible for converting sucrose into two simple isomeric sugars is",option:{a:"Invertase",b:"Amylase",c:"Lactose",d:"Maltase"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:82,question:"According to the kinetic theory, an increase in temperature causes the kinetic energy of particles to",option:{a:"Decrease",b:"Increase",c:"Remain constant",d:"Be zero"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:68,question:"A rock sample was added to cold dilute HNMO3. The gas evolved was passed into a solution of acidified K2Cr2O7 and the solution turned green. The rock sample contains",option:{a:"NO3-",b:"Cl-",c:"SO42-",d:"SO32-"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:177,question:"The ores that can be concentrated by flotation are",option:{a:"Nitride ores",b:"Chloride ores",c:"Oxide ores",d:"Sulphide ores"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:210,question:"When sulphur (IV) oxide is passed into a solution of sodium hydroxide for a long time. It eventually produces a solution of",option:{a:"Na2SO4",b:"NaHSO4",c:"Na2SO3",d:"NaHSO3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:108,question:"The salt that will form a precipitate soluble in excess ammonia solution is",option:{a:"Ca(NO3)2",b:"Cu(NO3)2",c:"Mg(NO3)2",d:"Al(NO3)3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:148,question:"Which of the following hydrogen halides has the highest entropy value",option:{a:"HF",b:"HCl",c:"HBr",d:"Hl"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:83,question:` I.  H = 1s1
II. O = 1s22s22p4
III. N = 1s22s22p3
IV. Zn = 1s22s22p63s23p64s23d10
From the above, which of the following pairs is likely to be paramagnetic?
`,option:{a:"I and II",b:"I and  III",c:"I    and IV",d:"III  and IV"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:78,question:"The filter in a cigarette reduces the nicotine content by",option:{a:"Burning",b:"Adsorption",c:"Evaporation",d:"Absorption"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:237,question:"Which of the following has an isomer",option:{a:"C4H10",b:"C6H6",c:"C2H4",d:"C2H6"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:156,question:"Aluminium hydroxide is used in the dyeing industry as a",option:{a:"Salt",b:"Dye",c:"Mordant",d:"Dispersant"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:263,question:"The droplets of water observed around a bottle of milk taken out of though refrigerator is due to the fact that the",option:{a:"Temperature of the milk drops as it loses heat into the surroundings",b:"Saturated vapour pressure of the milk is equal to the atmospheric pressure",c:"Water vapour in the air around loses some of its energy to the bottle",d:"Water vapour in the air around the bottle gains some energy from the bottle"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:24,question:" 2SO2(g) + O2(g) ⇌  2SO3(g)  The equilibrium constant for the reaction above is increased by  [ΔH = -189kJ mol -1]",option:{a:"Increasing the temperature of the system",b:"Increasing the pressure of the system",c:"The addition of a catalyst to the system",d:"Increasing the surface area of the vessel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:217,question:"Na2CO3(aq)  +  2HCI(aq)  → 2NaCI(aq)  +  H2O(l)  +  CO2(g)    How many moles of sodium trioxocarbonate (IV) are there in a 25cm3 solution which required 10cm3 of 0.05 mol dm-3 hydrochloric acid solution to neutralize it?",option:{a:"0.100mloe",b:"0.001mole",c:"1.000mole",d:"0.010mole"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:44,question:"When sodium reacts with water, the resulting solution is",option:{a:"weakly acdic",b:"neutral",c:"acidic",d:"alkaline"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:59,question:"25cm3 of a 0.2mol dm-3 solution of Na2CO3 requires 20cm3 of  solution of HCl for neutralization. The concentration of the solution is",option:{a:"0.6 mol dm-3",b:"0.5 mol dm-3",c:"0.4 mol dm-3",d:"0.2 mol dm-3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:1,question:"25cm3 of a gas X contains Zmolecules at 150C and 75mmHg. How many molecules will 25cmm3 of another gas Y contain at the same temperature and pressure",option:{a:"2Y",b:"2Z",c:"Z",d:"Y"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:19,question:"A metal M displaces zinc from zinc chloride solution. This shows that",option:{a:"M is more electronegative than zinc",b:"Zinc is above hydrogen in the series",c:"M is more electropositive than zinc",d:"Electrons flow from zinc to M"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:81,question:"The noble gases owe their inactivity to",option:{a:"Octet configuration",b:"Cyclic shape",c:"Hexagonal shape",d:"Obtuse configuration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:259,question:"The ion that will give a white precipitate with aqueous NaOH and soluble in excess of the base is",option:{a:"Zn2+",b:"Mg2+",c:"Ca2+",d:"Cu2+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:213,question:"Which of the following equimolar solutions will have the highest pH",option:{a:"NH4OH",b:"CH3COONa",c:"HCI",d:"NaOH"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:258,question:"The characteristic colour of the flame shown when a copper salt moistened with concentrated hydrochloric acid on platinum is put on a bunzen burner is",option:{a:"Green",b:"Lilac",c:"Yellow",d:"Brick-red"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:291,question:"When iron is exposed to moist air, it gradually rusts. This is due to the formation of",option:{a:"Anahydrous  iron (III) oxide",b:"Anhydrous iron (II) oxide",c:"Hydrated iron (II) oxide",d:"Hydrated iron  (III) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:111,question:"The modern process of manufacturing steel from iron is by",option:{a:"Treatment with acids",b:"Oxidation",c:"Blast reduction",d:"Treatment with alkalis"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:277,question:"Calculate the volume of 0.5 mol dm-3 H2SO4 that is neutralized by 25cm3 of 0.1 mol dm-3 NaOH",option:{a:"2.5cm3",b:"0.4cm3",c:"0.1cm3",d:"5.0cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:150,question:"Which of the following shows little or no net reaction when the volume of the system is decreased",option:{a:" H2(g)  +  l2(g)  ⇌  2Hl(g)",b:"2NO2(g)  ⇌  N2O4(g)",c:" PCl5(g)   ⇌ PCl3(g)  + Cl2(g)",d:" 203(g)   ⇌  3O2(g)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:302,question:"The haloalkanes used in the dry cleaning industries are",option:{a:"Chloroethane and dichloroethene",b:"trichloroethene and tetrachloroethene",c:"chloromethane and dichloroethene",d:"Trichloromethane and tetrachloromethane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:246,question:"Which of the following results in the fall of acid rain",option:{a:"Gaseous hydrocarbons",b:"Oxide of lead",c:"Particulate matter",d:"Oxides of sulphur"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:160,question:"Oxyacetylene flame is used for iron-welding because it",option:{a:" makes the iron metal solidity very quickly",b:"Combines with oxygen to give a pop sound",c:"Evolves a lot of heat when burnt",d:"Dissociates to produce carbon (IV) oxide and oxygen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:189,question:"The shape of the hydrocarbon compound CH4 is",option:{a:"Square planar",b:"Tetrahedral",c:"Planar",d:"Linear"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:170,question:"The property used in the industrial preparation of nitrogen and oxygen from air is",option:{a:"Rate of diffusion",b:"Solubility",c:"Density",d:"Boiling point"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:303,question:" Two hydrocarbons X and Y were treated with bromine water. Decolorized the solution and Y did not. Which class of compound does Y belong",option:{a:"Alkynes",b:"Alkenes",c:"Alkanes",d:"Benzene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:208,question:"A concentrated solution containing H+, Cu2+, OH- and Cl- was electrolyzed using platinum electrodes. The ion that will be discharged at the cathode is",option:{a:"OH-",b:"Cl-",c:"Cu2+",d:"H+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:104,question:"Chlorine gas is prepared in the laboratory by",option:{a:"Adding concentrated hydrochloric acid to solid manganese (IV) oxide",b:"Adding concentrated tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid to solid sodium chloride",c:"Dropping concentrated hydrochloric acid onto potassium tetraoxomanganate (VII) crystals",d:"Oxidizing concentrated hydrochloric acid using potassium heptaoxodichromate (VI) crystals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:180,question:"When pure aluminum metal is heated to red hot in the presence of nitrogen gas, the compound formed is",option:{a:"AI2N",b:"AIN",c:"AI2N2",d:"AI2N3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:146,question:"The mass of silver deposited when a current of 10A is passed through a solution of silver salt for 4830s is    [Ag = 108, F = 96500 Cmol-1]",option:{a:"108.0g",b:"54.0g",c:"27.0g",d:"13.5g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:89,question:"The structural component that makes detergent dissolve more quickly in water than soap is",option:{a:"–SO3 –Na+",b:"–COO-Na+",c:"–SO4- Na+",d:"–COO-K+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:49,question:"The chromatographic separation of ink is based on the ability of the components to",option:{a:"React with each other",b:"React with the solvent",c:"Dissolve in each other in the column",d:"Move at different speeds in the column"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:52,question:"The substance least considered as a source of environmental pollution is",option:{a:"Silicate minerals",b:"Uranium",c:"Lead compounds",d:"Organophosphorous compounds"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:31,question:"The general formula for the alkanals is",option:{a:"ROH",b:"R2CO",c:"RCOOR1",d:"RCHO"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:203,question:"The solubility curve shows the variation of solute concentration with",option:{a:"Volume",b:"Vapour density",c:"Pressure",d:"Temperature"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:280,question:"6AgNO3(aq)  +  PH3(g) +    3H2O(l)      →    6Ag(s)+   H3PO3(aq)   +    6HNO3(aq)  In the reaction above, the reducing agent is",option:{a:"H2O(l)",b:"PH3(g)",c:"AgNO3(aq)",d:"HNO3(AQ)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:41,question:"The gas that can best be collected by downward displacement of air is",option:{a:"Chlorine",b:"Sulphur(IV)oxide",c:"Ammonia",d:"Carbon(IV)oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:120,question:"The process by which atoms are rearranged into different molecular structures in the petroleum refining process is referred to as",option:{a:"Catalytic cracking",b:"Hydrocracking",c:"Polymerization",d:"Reforming"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:98,question:"If Y is an oxidizing agent that reacts with a reducing agent, Z, which of the following is correct",option:{a:"Y increases in oxidation number",b:"Y becomes reduced",c:"Z loses protons",d:"Z gains protons"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:253,question:"The sulphide which is insoluble in dilute hydrochloric acid is",option:{a:"CuS",b:"Na2S",c:"FeS",d:"ZnS"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:288,question:"To a solution of an unknown compound, a little dilute Tetraoxosulphate (IV) acid was added with some freshly prepared (II) Tetraoxosulphate (VI) Solution. The brown ring observed after the addition of a stream of concentrated  Tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid confirmed the presence of",option:{a:"CI",b:"SO",c:"NO",d:"CO"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:131,question:"The shape of the s-orbital is",option:{a:"Spherical",b:"Elliptical",c:"Spiral",d:"Circular"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:20,question:"Which of the following best explains the increase in the rate of a chemical reaction as the temperature rises",option:{a:"The bonds in the reacting molecules are more readily broken",b:"The molecules collisions become more violent",c:"A lower proportion of the molecules has the necessary minimum energy to react",d:"The collision frequency of the molecules increases"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:105,question:"Metals of the first transition series have special proper ties which are different from those of groups I and II elements because they have partially filled",option:{a:"s  orbitals",b:"p orbitals",c:"d orbitals",d:"f orbitals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:301,question:"One of the major uses of Alkanes is",option:{a:"In the hydrogenation of oils",b:"In the textile industries",c:"In the production of plastics",d:"As domestic and industrial fuels"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:107,question:"Which of the following statements is true of sulphur (IV) oxide",option:{a:"It forms Tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid with water",b:"It is an odourless gas",c:"It is an acid anhydride",d:"It forms white precipitate with acidified barium chloride"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:55,question:"Tetraoxosulphate(VI) acid burns the skin by",option:{a:"Heating",b:"Hydration",c:"Dehydration",d:"Hydrolysis"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:281,question:"The IUPAC nomencalatyre of the compound LiAIH4 is",option:{a:"Aluminium tetrahydrido lithium",b:"Tetrahydrido lithium aluminate (III)",c:"Lithium aluminium hydride",d:"Lithium tetrahydridoaluminate (III)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:36,question:"When chlorine is passed into water and the resulting solution exposed to sunlight, the product formed are",option:{a:"Chlorine gas and hydrogen",b:"Oxygen and oxochlorate(l) acid",c:"Hydrochloric acid and oxygen",d:""},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"}],n={message:e,subject:o,status:200,total:120,data:t};export{t as data,n as default,e as message,i as status,o as subject,a as total};
